vamtam.com 2018-10-03

# Privacy Policy – Vamtam Themes

  1. Hi, we’re VamTam  Ltd and welcome to our privacy policy. This policy sets out how we handle personal information.
  2. When we say ‘we’, ‘us’ or ‘VamTam’ it’s because that’s who we are and we own and run the Sites vamtam.com and all sub-domains.  Take the time to read this policy because it forms a part of the user terms for each of our Sites. By using any of our Sites, you agree to this policy. If you do not agree to this policy we won’t take it personally, but please do not use our Sites.

#### What type of personal information do we collect?

  1. We collect certain personal information about visitors and users of our Sites. The most common types of information we collect are things like: usernames, member names, email addresses, other contact details, support queries, and web analytics data.  Information or an opinion is your “personal information” if it is about you as an identified or identifiable individual.

#### How we collect personal information

  1. We may collect personal information directly when you provide it to us, automatically as you navigate through the Sites.
  2. When you provide personal information to us via the Sites you’re consenting to us collecting and using that information in line with this policy and the user terms of each of the Sites. You are likely to provide personal information when you complete Help Desk registration and buy items or services on our Sites, subscribe to a newsletter, email list, submit feedback,  fill out a survey, or send us a communication.

#### Personal information we collect about you from others

  1. Although we generally collect personal information directly from you, we may on occasion also collect information about you from other people (such as the payment provider account details required to process a transaction) and by using tracking technologies such as cookies, web beacons and other web analytics software or services.

#### How do we use personal information?

  1. We may use your personal information in order for us to: 
  2. operate the Sites and provide you with services described on the Sites, like to verify your identity when you sign in to the Help Desk, to facilitate and process transactions that take place on the Sites, to respond to support tickets and to help facilitate the resolution of any disputes
  3. update you with operational news and information about our Sites and services like to notify you about changes to our Sites, website disruptions or security updates
  4. provide you with information that you request from us or, where we have your consent to do so, provide you with marketing information about products and services which we feel may interest you
  5. carry out technical analysis to determine how to improve the Sites and services we provide
  6. monitor activity on the Sites, like to identify potentially fraudulent activity and to ensure compliance with the user terms that apply to the Sites
  7. manage our relationship with you, like by responding to your comments or queries submitted to us on the Sites or asking for your feedback or whether you want to participate in a survey
  8. manage our legal and operational affairs

#### When may we disclose your personal information?

  1. We may disclose personal information to people like: 
  2. our professional advisers (lawyers, accountants, financial advisers etc)
  3. regulators and government authorities in connection with our compliance procedures and obligations
  4. a purchaser or prospective purchaser of all or part of our assets or our business, and their professional advisers, in connection with the purchase
  5. other people where we are authorized or required by law to do so.

#### How do we store your personal information secure?

  1. We store personal information on secure servers that are managed by our service providers. Personal information that we store is subject to security and access controls, including username and password authentication and data encryption where appropriate.

#### How can you access your personal information?

  1. You can access some of the information that we collect about you by logging in to your Help Desk account. You also have the right to make a request to access other information we hold about you and to request corrections of any errors in that information. You may also close the account you have with us for any of our Sites at any time.

#### Control of your personal information

  1. Where we have your consent to do so (e.g if you have subscribed to one of our e-mail lists or have otherwise indicated that you are interested in receiving offers or information from us), we may send you marketing communications about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. You can ‘opt-out’ of such communications if you would prefer not to receive them in the future.
  2. If your e-mail address has changed and you would like to continue to receive our e-mails, you will need to access your account and update your e-mail address information in your account and sign-up again for those e-mails that you want to receive.
  3. If we send e-mails with commercial content we will generally include an “unsubscribe” facility that you can use to opt-out of further communications – to opt-out, just follow the instructions in the e-mail. We might not include an opt-out facility in important operational and service-based e-mails concerning things like your purchases, the user terms, important updates and need-to-know messages. By using our Sites you agree that we do not need to include opt-out facilities in those messages.
  4. You also have choices about cookies, as described below. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject cookies some parts of our Sites may not work properly in your case.

#### Cookies

  1. Generally speaking, when you visit our Sites, there’s certain information that’s recorded which is generally anonymous information and may not reveal your true super-hero identity. If you’re logged into your Help Desk account some of this information could be associated with your account. We’re talking about the following kinds of details: 
  2. your IP or proxy server IP
  3. basic domain information
  4. your Internet service provider is sometimes captured depending on the configuration of your ISP connection
  5. the date and time of your visit to the website
  6. the length of your session
  7. the pages which you have accessed
  8. the number of times you access our site within any month;
  9. the size of a file you look at
  10. the website which referred you to our Sites
  11. the operating system which your computer uses.

#### Information about children

Our Sites are not suitable for children under the age of 16 years, so if you are under 16 we ask that you do not use our Sites or give us your personal information (if you are a young tech wiz, please direct your nearest responsible adult to use the Sites for you!). If you are from 16 to 18 years, you can browse the Sites but you’ll need the supervision of a parent or guardian to become a registered user. It’s the responsibility of parents or guardians to monitor their children’s use of our Sites.

#### Information you make public or give to others

If you make your personal information available to other people, we can’t control or accept responsibility for the way they will use or manage that data. There are lots of ways that you can find yourself providing information to other people, like when you post a public message on a forum thread, share information via social media, or make contact with another user (such as a third party Author) whether via our Sites or directly via email. Before making your information publicly available or giving your information to anyone else, think carefully. If giving information to another user via our Sites, ask them how they will handle your information.  

#### How long we keep your personal information

We retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to provide the services to you and others, and to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your personal information or to provide you with our services, you can request that we erase your personal information. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information we will retain information from deleted accounts as necessary for our legitimate business interests, to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the terms of service and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### How can you contact us?

If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact us office@vamtam.com

#### If you’re a user or visitor in the European Economic Area these rights also apply to you: 

For the purposes of applicable EU data protection law (including the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), we are a ‘data controller’ of your personal information.

#### How you can access your personal information

You are also entitled to ask us to port your personal information (i.e. to transfer in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, to you), to erase it, or restrict its processing. You also have rights to object to some processing that is based on our legitimate interests, such as profiling that we perform for the purposes of direct marketing, and, where we have asked for your consent to process your data, to withdraw this consent as more fully described below.  
These rights are limited in some situations – for example, we can demonstrate that we have a legal requirement to process your personal information. In some instances, this means that we may retain some data even if you withdraw your consent.  
Where we require your personal information to comply with legal or contractual obligations, then provision of such data is mandatory: if such data is not provided, then we will not be able to manage our contractual relationship with you, or to meet obligations placed on us. In all other cases, provision of requested personal information is optional.

VamTam Privacy Policy, effective date 11 April 2018
